# **NOMAAN AHMED QADRI**

# Software Developer

+91-9797112660

in LinkedIn

#### **About Me**

DOB : 04/07/98

Gender: Male

Religion: Islam

Nationality: Indian

#### **Areas of Interest**

- SaaS.
- IoT.
- Neural Networks / Machine Learning.
- Cloud Infrastructure.

#### **Skills**

- NestJS
- ExpressJS
- NodeJS
- ReactJS
- JavaScript
- SQL
- Python
- Django
- C++
- .NET
- PostgreSQL
- PrismaORM
- Socket.io
- REDIS
- RABBITMQ
- HTML
- CSS
- JQuery
- Azure
- GIT

# **Summary**

I'm a computer science graduate working as a Software Engineer with more than 2 years of experience building web based software. My expertise lies in working with SaaS based products that solve management challenges by organizations. I have a good work ethic and an aptitude for problem solving, working with an attitude to deliver high quality results. I'm looking for a role that allows me to showcase my skills and also have a real impact on the world.

## **Work Experience**

Appsierra Solutions Pvt. Ltd.

Feb 2022 - Present

Associate Software Developer

- Designed, developed and maintaining API's and microservices using NodeJS, ExpressJS, NestJS with emphasis on efficiency, security and syncronisation for multiple SaaS platforms.
- Developed a custom **RBAC** system for a multi-tenant system.
- Designed and developed multiple databases based on PostgreSQL and implemented **PrismaORM** as an interface.
- Implemented RabbitMQ and REDIS for queuing and caching.
- Developed real-time communication and notifications using Socket.IO
- Developed and customized API's and management system using StrapiCMS.
- Developed Single Page Applications with ReactJS, NextJS with server-side rendering with a focus on speed, responsive design and SEO.
- Integrated APIs with validation and handling sensitive user data.
- Version control with Git/GitHub.
- Used Azure Suite for Task management, performance tracking and pipelines.

#### Edlyne Time Pvt. Ltd

Oct 2021-Jan 2022

Junior Software Developer

- Designed and developed a User Interface in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, iQuery.
- Developed a custom back-end Content Management System based in **Diango** based on **Python**.
- Handled user authentication and authorization.
- Developed and integrated API's with real-time stock market data sent to users.
- Version control with Git/GitHub.

### **Education**

Bachelors of Technology in Computer Science Central University of Kashmir, J&K 2017 - 2021